GIDI MEIR **MORRIS**

Software Developer & Engineering Manager

cv@gidi.io

London, UK

gidi.io

github.com/gmmorris

in uk.linkedin.com/in/ gidimorris

Primary Toolset

Technical Skills

Node.js, Javascript ES5+

Java 8+

CSS, SASS & their ilk

HTML, The DOM & Web APIs

Rxjs, React, Preact & their ilk

Compile-time tooling for JS runtimes

Functional & Reactive programming

Reactive system design

AWS, Terraform & Immutable Infrastructure

Test Driven Development

Automated Testing (browser & black-box)

Methodologies & Catalytic Skills

Individuals and Interactions over Processes and Tools

Extreme Programming, Scrum

Pair & Mob Programming

Mentorship & Collaboration

DevOps Practices

CICD, Travis, Jenkins Monitoring, Alerting & Structured Logging

Open Source Projects

on github.com/gmmorris

Jeff Goldblum (jg) A command-line JSON processor in Rust which searches for structures in JSON input and prints each matching object.

bs-rewire Bucklescript bindings for Rewire

Meze A Component Composition library for **Declaratively Composable Operations**

Safeobj Proxy based safe property access

Simmer Reverse CSS Selector Engine

In addition to releasing my own projects I have contributed over the years to several community Open Source projects such as Babel, highlights.js, mootools.

Profile

During my almost 20-year career in software development and engineering management, I have worked in a diverse and comprehensive array of technical and managerial roles spanning frontend, backend, and infrastructure. These roles have afforded me opportunities to lead at various levels and a variety of environments, from providing guidance and cohesive technical vision in high-scale, fast-pace start-ups, to ensuring consistent, sustainable, high-quality output within large enterprise companies. I am driven by a deep interest in agile practices, team dynamics, continuous improvement and mentorship which I hold as equally important to technical ability, in pursuit of successful product delivery. Alongside sustainably delivering high-quality work, I passionately believe in positively impacting my community in aspects ranging from technical achievement to diversity and inclusivity.

Work Experience

Elastic **Principal Software Engineer**

2019 - 2020

Full stack engineering of Elastic's Alerting framework within the Kibana Platform.

Focused on incremental delivery of performance improvements and scaling of Kibana's TaskManager to better handle the growth in adoption of our new Alerting framework.

Unruly Senior Software Developer

2016 - 2019

Engineering management of a 10+ person Extreme Programming development team providing mentorship and hands-on technical guidance.

Owner of the Programmatic Demand business strand, ensuring valuable prioritisation, research and implementation of deliverables in a lean, yet sustainable, manner.

Full stack development of the Unruly Ad Platform using Javascript & Java using immutable infrastructure on AWS.

Among other things this includes R&D of: Our Ad Exchange, a multi-region distributed system servicing thousands of requests a second. Our Supply Side Platform, a Web Application in React & Redux. A variety of Video Ad Formats and client side solutions in vanilla Javascript.

Working in an XP environment (agile, Pair & Mob Programming, Collective Ownership, & Merciless Refactoring), I have focused on collaboration, self organisation and mentorship across all aspects of product delivery and a variety of catalytic skills.

Stewardship of the Product Development Diversity & Inclusivity group. Unruly's first Nomad, providing roaming technical leadership across all development teams.

Loveholidays Lead Front-End Architect

2014 - 2015

Engineering management of a 7 person development team of *Javascript & Python* developers responsible for the Loveholidays Web Application, providing hands-on technical leadership and prioritisation.

Led the top down rewrite of the entire website (turning spaghetti into lasagne), converting a code base of legacy JS into a modular architecture based on Backbone.js and ES6. Incrementally rearchitected different parts of the site while still providing a stable code base for continued functional development.

https://gidi.io/cv/ 1/2

2013

Education

Officer Candidate School (IDF)

2006

Software Development Management

Professional diploma

Intensive 6 month course qualification as a Military Officer, covering Leadership and Team Building, with a specialisation in Project Management and Software Development Processes.

Mamram (IDF)

2003

Software Development Bootcamp

Professional diploma

Intensive 6 month course covering development and software design principles, actual work experience in a variety of development environments such as C, C++, ASP & Javascript, Java, Perl, SQL and PL-SQL and working environments such as Windows and Unix.

Kvutzat Yavne High School

2002

High School Diploma

Computer Science major

Who Am I Really?

I grew up in Israel where, after serving in the military for several years, I focused my efforts on finding my way into the Tel Aviv tech scene. I am also an accomplished photographer, having exhibited in Israel and London, completed commercial jobs for clients in the Israeli entertainment industry and taken part in major art fairs. I am a martial arts parctitioner and instructor, currently holding a 2nd Master grade at Wing Tsun Kung Fu. I am also an avid commentator on all things political and theological and was named one of Quora's Top Writers for 2014. I live in order to create, which is, I believe, why I have found such warm homes in both the startup scene and the art scene.

Freelance R&D and Consulting

Designed and implemented *Front End* solutions consisting of application development using *Backbone.js*, workflow, build and test automation using *Grunt.js* and Back End layers and APIs using *PHP Flight* and *Node.js Express*.

Built a responsive marketing website for a mobile product including animated UX demonstrations using *Bootstrap* and both *JS animations* and *CSS3 transitions*.

Implemented data storage and caching solutions using *Redis* and *MongoDB* running on top of *AWS*.

During this time I provided services for several different companies, including ReallyGood, Conduit, Klarna and Cyhawk Ventures.

Pluralis Senior Front End Developer

2011 - 2012

As the first employee at an early stage startup (pre round A) I was solely responsible for the design and implemention of the Front End architecture of our A/B testing product.

Using *Backbone.js*, *Underscore*, *jQuery*, *Bootstrap*, *LESS* and vanilla *Javascript*, I created a system for Multivariate A/B testing, an SDK for third-party developers and a web application for the management and execusion of A/B testing competitions.

I built several Javascript libraries, including a library for cross-build module management and a reverse CSS-selector engine for persistable DOM querying.

I supported development of a backend system using Java Spring and AWS. Implemented storage solutions using MongoDB and CouchDB.

Metacafe Web Engineer

2011 - 2010

Development of a Web Application using *PHP* and *Javascript* for the Metacafe portal and the site's semantic data layer in a high scale and high traffic web environment.

Designed, implemented and extended infrastructure packages using *PHP* for *Mediawiki*, *Semantic MediaWiki* and an in-house MVC web framework.

Integrated the Metacafe Semantic data layer with the Sesame RDF database.

Implemented caching layers using *Memcached* and *Varnish*, and tuned caching and eviction strategies in *PHP* and *VCL* in a massive scale environment (measuring several millions of request per day).

Implemented asynchronous workers using *Gearman* in *PHP* to perform offline processessing and semantic analysis of video content.

Military Application System Engineer

2009

Product Management, System Analysis and Oversight over the development of a multimillion dollar *Command & Control* system.

Military Team Lead, Army Captain

2006 - 2008

Engineering management of two development teams (8 people in total) working on two ASP.Net Web Applications.

Technical design and development of Web Applications and Services in *Javascript* and *C#*. Designed the data layer and integration with both the *Oracle 9i* and *SQLServer* databases.

Military Software Developer

2005 - 2003

Developed an N-Tier ASP.Net web application as part of a four person team. Built both UI and BL components for data display and manipulation using Javascript and C# libraries. Created and took ownership of a department wide position responsible for all UX and design work.

Freelance Web Designer

2002

Freelance graphic designer, servicing both private clients and companies such as HP's Indigo division.

https://gidi.io/cv/